Logging on to Discovery

SSH via command line:

	1.	Logon to the NMSU VPN using Cisco AnyConnect VPN Client
			• vpn.nmsu.edu/hpc
			• Enter username in the popup window
			• Enter password in the next popup window
			• Enter uniquely generated code (from FreeOTP or similar) in final popup window

	2.	Open a secure shell with Discovery (Mac/Linux – Terminal, Windows – PuTTy, 
		ChromeOS – SecureShell)
			• ssh username@discovery.nmsu.edu
			• Enter password*
				* Note – No characters will appear on the screen, but you ARE in fact typing your password. Recommend copying and pasting to avoid problems with typing in a complex password

Browser access via Open OnDemand:

	1. Type the following URL into your browser: https://ondemand.nmsu.edu/

	2. Enter username, password, and one-time code (from FreeOTP or similar)

	3. Proceed to the “Files” tab, where you can open a browser-based terminal session, upload/download files, and compose bash jobs.
